DR. PHILIPP STASSEN



@ philipp.stassen@gmail.com

www.philippstassen.github.io

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING: OCaml, Haskell, Python, Agda, Shell, Html/CSS, LaTex SOFTWARE: Coq, Emacs, Git, Iris, Mathematica, Docker

LANGUAGES

MOTHERTONGUE: German FLUENT: English BASIC: Spanish, Danish

CONTACT Richard-Strauss-Str 23 81677 Munich Germany

ABOUT ME

Computer Science PhD with a strong theoretical and mathematical background, specializing in modelling programs and algorithms with the goal to understand their operational behaviour and verify correctness. Skilled in connecting and coordinating across teams, with expertise and adaptability to contribute to a wide array of topics effectively.

EXPERTISE Programming languages, algorithms, probabilistic programming, program verification, machine learning, functional programming languages, mathematical modelling, type theories, safety and security of cyber physical systems

EXPERIENCE

PHD FELLOW

09.2020 - 06.2024

Aarhus university, Department of Computer Science

CONFERENCE TALKS

- Types for Proofs and Programs 2022
- Workshop on the Implementation of Type Systems 2022

TEACHING

- \bullet Teaching Assistant in Computability and Logic 2021&2022 Publications
- A flexible multimodal proof assistant
 - Modelling Recursion and Probabilistic Choice in Guarded Type Theory

INTERNSHIP

II.2022 - 04.2023

Airbus Defence and Space

R&D project about safety and security of modern aviation as part of the EU projects Albatros and Concordia.

I conducted the relevant research and collected functional requirements from internal and external stakeholders. ACHIEVEMENTS

Publication "Don't Panic! Analysing the Impact of Attacks on the Safety of Flight Management Systems" (Best paper award at DASC 2023)

EDUCATION

PHD STUDENT

09.2020 - 06.2024

Aarhus university, Department of Computer Science

THESIS Programming language semantics in modal type theories
DEFENCE Friday 9 August 2024

MASTER OF SCIENCE

2018 - 2020

Stockholm University, Mathematics

AWARD Mittag-Leffler prize for Masterthesis

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

2014-2018

University Bonn, Mathematics